Clyde Clarke, Ph.D.

Washington DC, 20032

https://www.linkedin.com/in/drclarke/ • 410-262-4421 • clyde.clarke@gmail.com

Data Scientist

Multifaceted data science and statistics instruction and field engineering career for 10+ years.

Technically sophisticated Data Scientist with advanced education and training in statistics and electrical/computer engineering combined with practical experience as a field engineer and instructor. Broad knowledge and success in algorithms, principles, and implementations of data science. Expert in statistical analysis, including programming languages (Python, R, MATLAB, and more).

Statistical Analysis and Modeling / Project Management / User Training and Support Strategic Research and Analysis / Troubleshooting & Issue Resolution

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Tools: MATLAB, R, C/C++, Image Processing, Numerical Modeling, COMSOL, Machine Learning, DSP/FPGA, Statistical Analysis, Python, MySQL, LabView.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Field Service Engineer (6/2017 - 3/2019)

AC4S, Washington DC

Technical Scope: SQL, LANs, Microprocessors

Develop databases and Entity Relationship Diagrams leveraging SQL and cutting-edge data analytics tools. Oversee troubleshooting, maintenance, and service of commercial building lighting control systems and lighting control systems components. Assess and analyze data from numerous devices to streamline and improve operations, reliability, and functionality. Create visual lighting system models and establish LANs for lighting control systems. Liaise with clients and end-users to ensure comprehensive understanding of lighting systems operations and functionality.

Key Achievements:

- Established a reputation for consistent and reliable service with a 96% customer approval rating.
- Consistently achieved 100% budget and time targets in the installation of lighting control systems for commercial properties
- Consistently completed commissioning ahead of target date schedule
- Enhanced customer maintenance capabilities by developing standard operations and troubleshooting procedures for new systems.
- Prepared detailed reports for management regarding software detects affecting installation, operation, and preventive maintenance.

Statistics Instructor (8/2011 - 6/2017)

Montgomery College, Germantown, MD

Technical Scope: Regression and Bayesian Analysis, Probability Distributions etc

Created and taught dynamic statistics coursework with a focus on environmental biology for undergraduate students.

...Continued...

Clyde Clarke, Ph.D.

Page Two

Statistics Instructor (8/2011 – 6/2017)

Montgomery College, Germantown, MD

Oversaw statistical projects as tools to deepen student learning, worked one-on-one with students to develop critical thinking skills, and delivered engaging presentations. Analyzed data sets to track and improve overall student progress leveraging advanced Microsoft Excel techniques.

Additional Instructor Experience:

Digital Signal Processing Instructor - MORGAN STATE UNIVERSITY - Baltimore, MD (2011)

Statistics Instructor - UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND UNIVERSITY COLLEGE - Largo, MD (2010 to 2011)

Statistics Instructor - PRINCE GEORGES COMMUNITY COLLEGE - Largo, MD (2008 to 2010)

Computer Technology Instructor - SOJOURNER DOUGLASS COLLEGE - Baltimore, MD (2006 to 2007)

Teacher's Assistant - MORGAN STATE UNIVERSITY - Baltimore, MD (2002 to 2003)

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Electrical and Computer Engineering (2009)

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Electrical and Computer Engineering (Summa Cum Laude, Salutatorian)

Morgan State University, Baltimore, Maryland

Honors: David and Lucille Packard Fellowship, Morgan State University Scholarship.

Academic Positions

Post-Doctoral Fellow – JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY, Medical Ultrasound Imaging and Intervention Collaboration Lab (MUSiiC), 2008 to 2010.

(Developed algorithms and experiments in support of medical ultrasound technology innovation.)

Dissertation Research – JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY, Computational Sensory Motor Labs (CSML), 2003 to 2008.

(Created SVM algorithm for ultrasonic beamformer, programmed quadratic optimization algorithms in C, developed a finite difference time domain (FDTD) model of wave propagation in tissue, and more.)

Undergraduate Research – MORGAN STATE UNIVERSITY, Advanced Realization and Characterization of Architectures for DSP Engineering (ARCADE).